[Music]
welcome to this business Central launch
event video about what's new in Al go
for GitHub on quality and testability my
name is Freddy Christensen I'm a
technical evangelist with Microsoft in
Copenhagen and together with me I have
my name is Sebastian and I'm a software
engineer at Microsoft and I recently
joined the team late December last year
we are happy for that now in this Rel
these we actually added support for page
scripting tests so you might have seen
that page scripting uh recording was
introduced in business Central quite
some time ago but half a year ago in
version 2024 Wave 2 we shipped the BC
replay npm module with that module it's
possible to to run page scripting test
in a workflow shortly after we released
that in algo for GitHub and we actually
demoed that at directions last year uh
but it wasn't included in the first
version so it's kind of like included in
the version that we are presenting now
we didn't include it in our launch event
videos last time but let's demo how that
actually
works yeah I will demo how we can run
page scripting tests in algo for
GitHub so here I have a simple uh single
project
repository and I have a folder called
recordings inside this folder I have
placed free page scripting files
generated uh using business Central
using the page roting test
functionality inside my uh project
settings I have used a page rting test
um setting to point to the recordings
folder
this will automatically pick up any
recording uh inside this folder ending
on a yml file
type this is an array so you can point
to several different folders if you have
many um but we also support pattern
matching if you give it an
Asterix yml uh it will point to anything
matching that pattern or you could point
to a specific file say I only want to
run this file I can point to this
specific file only and the other two
will be ignored so how does this
look you already know about the test
result visualizer that has existed for a
while what is new is the page scripting
test result visualizer as you can see it
looks similar but it gives you a quick
overview of all the tests uh and whether
they passed or not in this case they all
passed if there was a failure
uh you can find more details by
downloading the result artifact down
here and looking at the extended locks
which includes a video of the test which
will show you what exactly went wrong I
would like to present how we can include
test apps during
deployment we have two features we want
to support number one is deploying test
apps uh and number two is automatically
running tests for this presentation we
have implemented the first
version um and all you have to do is
prepare your online environment which
should be a Sandbox
environment and then enable this feature
in Alco
settings this is under the deploy to
structure which you have used many times
before uh for your deployment to
environments on top of that uh we now
also have the option to exclude
apps by ID when you deploy so in case
you want to test only a specific app you
can out do
that uh and let's run a demo showing how
this works here I have a symbol
repository uh a single project
repository with two apps uh and two test
apps what I want to do is deploy app one
alongside the two test apps so app one
app one. test and app one. performance
test I want to exclude app
2 in my repository settings in GitHub
Alo settings. Json and I'll
Define two new things in my deploy to
structure I Define include test apps in
sandbox environment as
true and exclude app IDs which is an
array and in here I put the ID of app
2 now when I run my uh publish to
environment this will automatically
deploy the test apps and exclude uh app
2 to show how this looks I will go to my
environment and here I have my list of
extensions we'll see here that app1 was
deployed and app 1. test was deployed
however the performance test app was not
deployed well that is intentional the
performance test app depends on a test
Library which is not available as an
appsource app and that automatically
gets picked up during deployment and
excluded so if you depend on something
that is start in appsource gallery it
will not be included this also works if
you have a custom deployment
script if this setting is enabled then
all your test apps will be passed to
your deployment script and you simply
have to handle dependency installation
on your own thanks for watching this
video and see you again next
time thank you